<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollView</string>
    <string name="rub">Royal University of Bhutan</string>
    <string name="gcit">Gyelpozhing College of Information Technology</string>
    <string name="information">
        <b>RUB</b>
        The Royal University of Bhutan was launched on 2nd June 2003 to provide tertiary education in Bhutan.
        The Royal Charter and the Statutes provide the legal instruments for the University.

        The overall rationale of the University as set out in the Royal Charter and Statutes is the "dissemination of
        knowledge and the advancement of learning through a balanced, well regulated and sound tertiary education system
        for the economic and cultural development of the Kingdom of Bhutan and to promote the cultural enrichment, personal
        development and well being of our people."

        The specific objectives of the University are:

        to develope and provide programmes of study at tertiary education level, of relevance and good quality which will
        fulfill the needs of the country for an educated and skilled population, and
        to promote and conduct research, to contribute to the creation of knowledge in an international context and to promote
        the transfer of knowledge of relevance to Bhutan.
        (Royal Charter and the Statutes of the Royal University of Bhutan 2003:3)

        RUB Vision, Mission and Core Values

        VISION
        An internationally recognized university steeped in GNH values

        MISSION
        To provide programmes of study at tertiary education level, of relevance and good quality which will fulfill the needs
        of the country for an educated, skilled and humane population;
        To promote and conduct research to contribute to the creation of knowledge of relevance to Bhutan, and
        To provide training and professional services for the enhancement of knowledge, capacity building and community development.

        <b>GCIT</b>
        The Gyalposhing College of Information Technology, officially inaugurated on 6th October, 2017 is one of the integral
        colleges of the Royal University of Bhutan. The decision to establish Gyalpozhing College of Information Technology was
        made during the meeting held on February 2, 2017 at the Hon’ble Prime Minister’s Office. In line with the decision, the
        chairman of Tertiary Education Board issued an executive order no. Ref No. MoE/EO/2017/4513 dated 20 February 2017 to
        establish the College. The institute is 24 kilometers away from Mongar town stretching an area of 62 acres of land
        engulfed by lush green mountains. The university is one of the three new colleges established in Eastern Bhutan with the
        VISION to be the ‘Center of Excellence in information Technology steeped in GNH values’. The college at its initial stage
        offers undergraduate programme in Bachelors of computer applications. The programme is taught by qualified and dedicated
        local and expatriate faculties.The methodology of “Learning by Doing” is a unique one adopted by GCIT. It aims at giving
        hands- on experience which helps the students understand the practical implementation aspects and the concepts associated
        with it.Furthermore, the college aims to diversify the programmes by including more practical and job-oriented course in
        the long-run.
    </string>
</resources>